Why?
Do you miss me already?
Nero...
we need to talk.
How was your sleep? Was it good?
The truth is, I didn't sleep well last night.
I kept thinking about what Don Ferell said.
We should know who killed Alyanna.
Don't you remember anything, buddy? Anything.
Just a little.
Maybe I can remember
the shape of the head, the shape of his eyes.
My grandfather once said...
that if you return
to the scene of the crime...
it might trigger
and make you remember what happened.
Federico.
Why don't we go back
to the scene of the crime?
Florence, sorry, but there's trouble again.
Hey Ferell guys, what did you do again?
This spells trouble again.
- Surprise!
No more talking about
Florence being an Almero.
In this space, she is just Florence.
There are a lot of things
we need to talk about,
like how is she and Nero.
And what's the stage of their relationship.
How about you, Florence? Do you have plans?
I don't know what to answer.
It seems for the first time in my life...
I have no plans.
How can you dream
if you have an influential family?
I don't know
what kind of future is waiting for us.
But what I only know is...
I love you so much.
And I love you so much too,
Nero Sebastian Araneta Ferell.
Come on, please answer.
Sorry, the subscriber cannot be reached.
Sir, I saw this among Celestina's belongings.
So this is the reason
why you're acting that way?
You're still talking to him?
Do you still allow him to brainwash you?
You would rather believe him
than your own father?
You are not leaving this house.
I will fix your papers
and we will leave as soon as possible.
- Baste?
- Sir?
Keep an eye on her.
I don't want her talking to someone else.
I will not let the Ferells
turn my own child against me.
What's happening here?
Sorry, the subscriber cannot be reached.
Nero?
Is that Florence?
Yes, Mother.
Wow, you're calling her mother.
"Son-in-law" is your peg.
If you're able to contact her,
can I talk to her too?
That's the thing, Mother.
She didn't answer her call.
Maybe the battery is low.
Or maybe she got caught.
Maybe she got caught
talking to you guys secretly,
that's why her father got mad
and confiscated her phone.
Patotina, you're overreacting.
Maybe there's no signal at home,
or her phone is turned off.
Well Nero, if you're able to contact her,
I want to talk to her too.
Maybe she needs something.
I'll just send it to the school
and you can hand it over to her.
Okay, Mother.
What are you doing?
I'm trying to be a father.
With what you're doing,
you are driving her away from us.
So what should I do?
She's testing me.
She's testing my patience
when it comes to the Ferells.
Garpidio talked to me.
Why?
He wanted to talk about Florence.
Why? What does he care?
Florence is important
to him and his grandsons,
and he wants us
to fix the misunderstanding our family has,
for her.
He killed my wife.
He killed the love of my life.
You don't understand that either?
We don't know that, Lorenzo!
We felt he had something to do with Alyanna,
but we were not able to prove anything.
You let the Ferells fool you again?
They are influential people here in Levante.
Of course, they can hide their crimes.
You know, this is my fault.
Because I've inculcated my anger
towards Garpidio in you.
And now, it's affecting your relationship
with your daughter.
You know, that's the problem with you.
You're already old,
that's why you tend to forget things,
and as a result,
it's easy for the Ferells to fool you.
How dare you?
Hello, guys. What's up?
Is everything okay?
What do you need?
Dad, calm down.
Sorry, the subscriber cannot be reached.
Hey, what's the problem?
I can't contact Florence.
Her phone has been unattended
since last night.
Didn't we tell you that maybe she's busy?
We designated a time to talk.
Besides, that's supposed to be the schedule
for her to talk to her mother and father.
It's very unlikely of her
to miss her call appointment.
Exactly.
Wait, Nero is here.
- Nero.
- Who's that?
It's the girls. They want to talk to you.
- Nero, are you there?
- Yes.
Were you able to talk to Florence?
That's what we were talking about.
I can't contact her since last night.
She's also not here.
And it's so unlikely for her
to miss this meeting.
Especially since we need
the head of the Communication Arts
to plan the season ender event of our school.
I'm sorry but I wasn't able to talk to her,
and I also don't have an idea where she is.
Which makes me worry, Nero.
Why?
Well, on my way here,
I overheard my dad talking
to Mr. Lorenzo Almero,
Florence's dad.
I heard that he was asking for my dad's help
to expedite the processing
of Florence's papers.
What for?
I wasn't able to hear the complete details,
but expediting travel documents
could only mean one thing.
I think
the Almeros are taking Florence away from us.
I think her dad is sending her
to live and study abroad.
Mr. Baste.
And if there's a victim here, that's you.
You're a victim of your own anger.
You're a victim of the pain you felt
when you lost Mommy.
Why?
Because you weren't able to protect her.
You failed to save her.
That's why you're looking
for someone else to blame
because of your own failure.
Because you knew deep in you
that you once neglected your family.
That's why you lost me, right?
Enough!
Go to your room!
Pack your bags.
I'm pulling you out of the university
and taking you with me to the States.
Hi.
Florence?
Am I right?
You're Florence?
Yes, I'm Florence.
But I think it should be Celestina,
because that's my real name.
Celestina...
But just between you and me,
I think I prefer to call you Florence.
Just like the beautiful place in Italy.
It's Florence.
I'm Samuel.
Your Uncle Samuel.
Uncle Samuel?
Yes.
I'm your father's brother.
Well, we're not blood-related, but...
your Grandpa Roger treated me as a real son.
And there,
maybe they failed to introduce me to you,
because they're very protective
when it comes to you.
Is that why they practically lock me up
here in the mansion
and force me to move to another country
even if I don't want to?
You know, Florence, I understand you.
And I understand the fear of a father.
But soon, when you become a parent,
you'll understand everything.
You'll know where your father is coming from.
I understand him...
and his fears.
But...
should we live in fear
for the rest of our lives?
You're right.
I understand you.
And because I understand you...
I can help you escape from the mansion.
Do you want that?
Really?
The Almeros will bring Florence
to the States.
Antonia overheard her dad,
and they're expediting
the processing of her papers.
That's unacceptable, Grandpa.
She was excellent in school.
Why does she have to study abroad?
Yes, Grandpa.
Why are they sending Florence to the States?
The discrimination against Asians
is too much there.
We should stop this, Grandpa.
We should take Florence back from them.
Stop this nonsense.
No one is going to do anything.
We should respect the rights of the Almeros.
Really, Grandpa?
You'll just let them?
You won't do anything?
You'll just leave Florence to them?
Nero, lower your voice.
You're still talking to your grandfather.
You can't always do things your way
all the time.
I spoke to Rogelio.
I beg him for us
to settle this thing between us,
for Florence's sake.
He didn't forgive me.
He even warned me.
He warned all of us to stay away from her.
And Lydia, I'm sorry, I'm afraid.
We have no choice.
I did everything I could do, but I failed.
So...
Do you understand now
what your grandpa meant?
If we keep insisting to be close to Florence,
the conflict between the Ferells and the Almeros
can escalate.
Florence will have a harder time.
And the best thing we could do right now
is just to...
let her be.
You're saying that
because you're not getting hurt
with everything that's happening now.
Nero?
Grandpa, I'll take care of him.
This scrambled egg that you cooked
is delicious.
The rumors are true.
You're a good cook, Florence.
- Thank you.
- It's so delicious.
I thought
I'll be able to get out of the mansion
and you'll help me escape,
but you just took me to the kitchen
so I can cook for you.
It turns out you're hungry.
I'm sorry.
You know
that's just about what your Uncle Samuel can do.
But I know the guards.
You can come out of your room anytime.
That's better than just staying in my room.
If I stay in there any longer,
I'll get bored to death.
That's why, still, thanks to you.
Thank you
because you were able to convince the guards.
That's nothing.
You know what?
You're a good and kind kid.
I remember your mom carrying you.
It seems all of you are saying
you remember Mommy carrying me.
The truth is...
I've been having dreams of her before.
But I don't know if it's just a dream.
If only she is still here.
Maybe things will be better if she was here.
If only she was here
to make dad understand...
and for our family to be complete.
No anger...
no ill feelings.
No fears.
And most importantly...
we're just happy.
I'm sorry
if I'm boring you
with everything I'm feeling.
Imagine, we've only just met,
but I'm boring you with all this
when all you wanted is to just eat.
You know, you're really like your mom.
She was like that too.
She always tries to make us laugh,
even if the situation is problematic.
She could even manage to crack some jokes.
But remember, I told you...
I don't like how your dad calls the shots.
That's why I can't just watch on
while you're having a hard time.
Because I made a promise
to your Mommy Alyanna...
that I'll make sure
that her daughter will fine...
and happy.
Well...
I can't just...
make the decisions.
I can't meddle with your father's decisions.
It's you who should decide, not me.
What do you mean?
Baste?
Can you please get us another juice?
Let's go. Come on.
Come with me.
What's this for?
Your dad and I call this
the secret stairs to success.
Why?
If you pass by these stairs,
you will become successful?
No, these are the stairs we take...
if you know, if we're grounded by our daddy.
This is where we pass
so we can escape from the mansion.
Escape from the mansion?
Yes.
Didn't I tell you
that only you can decide for yourself?
If you want what your dad is doing to you...
then go with him to America.
But if not...
this is your chance to escape from here.
Or you can go back
to the parents you grew up with.
But if you do that...
you must not show yourself to them.
Because for sure, your grandfather and daddy
will go looking for you.
And if that happens,
your life will be complicated.
Not only yours,
but the lives
of your mother and father as well.
Hey Nero, wait.
Where are you going?
I need to go out and cool down.
What are you doing?
I'll go with you.
I need to cool down too.
Can you, please?
Just let me be alone.
Let you be alone?
I'm sorry, dude, but I can't do that.
When we are alone, we tend to be impulsive
and do stupid things
that we will regret for the rest of our lives.
So, whether you like it or not,
I'll go with you.
I'm sorry.
I'm just shocked by what is happening.
I thought everything is okay...
But now, Florence will be far away from us.
She will be okay, Lydia.
I'm sure that she will find a way
to connect with you and Federico.
You know what?
No distance can separate a child...
who loves the family that she knows.
But you know, USA is still different.
I have a friend who went to California.
When he came back here,
he doesn't know me already.
Hey, stop it, James.
You're making things harder.
You know
that Lydia is going through a lot right now.
So shut up.
I'm not worried about that, James.
I'm not worried if she'll forget about us,
or if she speaks fluent English
when she comes back.
What's bothering me
is the fact that she's so far away from us.
What if she's all alone?
What if she's sad?
What if she needs someone to talk to,
or someone to lean on?
It breaks the heart of any mother...
if she knows that her child has no ally
or someone to depend on
in a different country.
Do not underestimate Florence.
I once belittled the heart of that child.
I thought
that she wouldn't stay long with the Ferells,
but I was very mistaken.
Because now...
she has changed this house.
And everyone is affected
by the news that she's leaving.
You're right about that.
I'll just tell Federico.
As for me...
I hope he won't feel too bad,
because his heart might not be able
to handle it.
Wait...
Where are Federico, Dencio, and Iking?
How come I haven't seen them
for quite some time?
Are you sure where we're going?
We're getting lost already.
Don't pressure me. That was 17 years ago.
Wait.
I remember something.
There. Wait, hold on.
- Okay, go.
- Yes, that's right.
Okay, okay.
Wait, wait. Okay.
- Okay, go.
- What now?
- Okay.
- There's a delicious Bulaluhan here.
- Over there.
- Really?
Yes. Let's go there.
Good thing you remembered something, somehow.
That's a good start.
- Ouch.
- Let's go. Hurry.
It seems this field trip of ours is useless.
I can't remember anything.
Just relax.
Buddy, remember, we have a saying
that virtue is a patience.
That's right.
Virtue is a patience.
And this is a good idea.
Who knows?
Once you've tasted
the delicious beef soup here...
it will trigger again your old memory
that is sleeping in your subconscious.
You know what?
Iking, you know a lot of things.
Well, being prompt beats being diligent,
but a person who is wise
beats the diligent and prompt person.
That's a nice quote.
Wow, that's possible.
Here it is.
There, there...
Yes, this is delicious.
More brains, more chances of winning.
More brains, more power.
Wait. Wait for a second.
Waitress, this includes...
- Salsa.
We've run out of salsa, Sir.
- There's no more salsa.
- Yes.
There's a different salsa I know.
Yes, go ahead and show them.
- Salsa, salsa.
- Salsa, baby.
Federico, salsa.
Just relax, buddy,
and for sure you'll remember it.
- Go on. Think harder.
- Stop it.
He's hungry already.
♪ Federico ♪
♪ Salsa, salsa ♪
♪ Salsa ♪
Look...
I do not profess
that I understand what you're feeling.
A part of me is jealous
that you found someone like Florence.
A part of me is also relieved
that I'm not going through your struggles.
That's why I'm not in the position
to give advice.
But being the eldest among us five...
allow me to try.
I don't need your help.
Unless you help me get inside
the mansion of the Almeros,
to get Florence.
And then what?
You'll elope
and you'll live happily ever after?
Whatever.
As long as we're together.
It's romantic...
your idea of just running away.
But sometimes, we need to face the truth...
that you and Florence bring out
a lot of complications.
At the end of the day...
you're a Ferell.
And she's an Almero.
Stop the car.
Hey, Nero! Where are you going?
Florence?
What's happening?
I saw Florence.
Maybe your eyes are just
playing tricks on you.
I can't make a mistake.
I really saw her face.
There's nothing.
Let's go.
Nero?
He is tall, just like Dingdong Dantes.
Let's focus on the face. Face.
He has a long face...
and his eyes are deep set, like that.
And this, I remember.
He has a mole on his nose.
What, Iking?
Did you get it?
Maybe that's another cartoon character.
No. This time, it's for real.
- Look, this is a real person.
- Let me see.
Federico, look at this.
This is the one.
He's the man I saw. I'm sure.
Who is that?
I think I saw him around when it was 4:30 PM.
Gio Alvarez.
I beg to disagree.
Let me see, buddy.
Gio Alvarez?
No, Iking, this looks like Bobby Andrews,
the guy in TGIS.
Yes, that's TGIS.
Right? The one from TGIS.
Why do you have a drawing of Mr. Samuel?
- Samuel?
Do you know this person?
Yes, he often comes here.
That's Mr. Samuel. Samuel Almero.
Celestina?
I'm sorry, Nero, but I need to go.
And besides, no one should see us together.
So just go home to the mansion,
and don't tell anyone that you saw me.
And you too, Tristan.
Wait, what are you talking about?
I'll go to a faraway place, Nero...
all by myself.
Well, I'll go with you.
Nero, I already told you
that it's not possible.
You'll only get involved.
Everyone will be involved
with my problem now.
And things will be more complicated.
Florence...
I am involved in everything
that will happen to you...
when I chose you.
When I decided to love you...
I've already accepted all your complications.
Nero, please.
I'm sorry, Florence...
but I will never leave your side.
Call me irrational...
but others are saying
that I'm a hopeless romantic.
But what's wrong with that?
What's wrong with being stupid?
What's wrong with losing everything...
if I'm with the person I love so much?
I'm sorry, Florence...
but I will never leave your side.
I will never leave you...
whether you like it or not.
- How about her clothes in the room?
- Celestina?
- Is it still there?
- Celestina!
Celestina! Dad, where is she?
Celestina is missing.
Calm down. I've already asked our guards
to look for her.
Dad, Celestina is missing.
We've checked every corner of the mansion,
but Miss Florence is no longer around.
I mean Celestina.
Where is Celestina?
Dad, look, how can I calm down?
My daughter is missing again!
This is all your fault, Lorenzo...
You're the reason why Florence is rebelling.
Her name is Celestina.
And what do you know about being a father?
Don't interfere with family matters.
Calm down, that's enough.
Choose your words, Lorenzo.
Your anger won't help right now.
What's important is we have to figure out
where Florence went.
I think I have an idea where she went.
So, this is your plan?
For both of you to leave
and go to a faraway place?
I won't go back to the mansion.
I don't want to go to the States.
I won't allow them to just force me
to do what they want.
So, you'll both go to a faraway place?
Why not?
What do you mean why not?
You won't survive.
I know how to cook.
I can sell food again.
I can work as a fish porter in the market.
Or let's just go back to the mansion?
No, that's not possible.
I don't want to go back to Mother and Father.
If the Almeros find out,
they'll be dragged into this again.
I don't want Grandpa Garp's situation
to be complicated.
That might spell more problems
with the Almeros.
Do you think the Almeros won't find you?
What if we change our names?
I'll be Sophia.
And I'll be Allen.
Hey, this is serious.
You guys cannot do this alone.
Don't decide impulsively.
At the very least,
let's talk to our friends first.
If not me,
it'll be them who'll be able to
talk sense to the both of you.
Go ahead and board.
Just move.
And your payment, please.
Guys, let's just take it easy.
We'll be dealing with the Almeros.
If we take a swipe,
we have to be sure that it's a bullseye.
Because if not,
this will all land on our faces.
What evidence do we need to prove
that Samuel has nothing to do
with Florence and Alyanna?
Why was he at the scene of the crime?
All I'm thinking about is Florence right now.
It's like my heart will explode
whenever I'm thinking that she's staying
with a murderer in the same house.
Don't worry.
I'm sure Grandpa Garp will do everything
to protect Florence.
Thank you.
I hope nothing bad will happen to Florence.
Because if not, all hell will break lose.
I will make them pay.
Celestina?
Come out now.
What are you doing here?
Where is Celestina?
Florence is not here.
Just cut to the chase, Mr. Garpidio.
This is the only place where she can go,
that's why I know you're hiding her.
You are wrong, Lorenzo.
Maybe instead of asking if Florence is here,
you should ask yourselves
why she ran away from you.
Please, Mrs. Dela Cruz.
Don't meddle here.
Why not?
You took my daughter from me.
And now that she's missing,
you're still looking for her here?
All my life...
that girl never left my sight.
All my life, I know where she is.
Where she sleeps, and what time she wakes up.
And now she's missing,
you're looking for her here?
We were living a quiet life.
And then you came and told us
that you're her real family?
You should be ashamed.
You're so thick-skinned.
If there's something I know about Florence,
it's that she'll never leave your side
if she knows and feels real love from you.
I just hope...
I do hope Florence is here.
I hope she went back to our house...
Because if that happens,
I will never give her back to you,
even if you kill me.
You can never get my daughter back.
Guys?
- It's Florence.
- Florence.
What are you doing?
- Are you okay?
- Where have you been?
We went to Antonia when we learned
that you have an issue in the mansion.
We wanted to know more details.
See?
We were just talking about you,
and all of a sudden you're here already.
I'm so sorry, Florence, this is all my fault.
I was so eager to post on my account.
I'm sorry.
Camille, don't apologize.
It's not your fault.
Don't stop yourself
just because other people have issues.
Still, she could've been more careful.
A little bit of sensitivity can go a long way.
She knows the issue
between the Almeros and Ferells.
When I heard that her dad showed that post,
I already sensed that you'll be in trouble,
especially when Antonia told us
about your dad's request
to fix your travel documents.
But, we didn't expect
that his reaction would be that big.
I mean, really?
Will they actually pull you out of Gyronella?
Even worse, live and go to school abroad?
Believe me, Antonia,
I don't agree with their decision,
but it's also coming from a good place.
Wait, but why do you look that way?
You don't look like an Almero.
You look like a criminal
hiding from the authorities.
It looks like you also don't agree
with your father's decision.
The reason why I brought them here,
is because I told them
to talk about their plan.
- Plan?
- What plan?
They plan to be impulsive and stupid.
We plan to go to a faraway place.
To elope and live together.
Away from all these problems.
What?
OMG!
Wow!
Maybe we can all calm down.
I know the emotions you are feeling now
are intense.
We all have ill feelings...
that come from them.
Maybe you have forgotten.
Florence is still missing.
It's better if we look for her first
before you nag at each other.
You animal!
- You're an animal! Animal!
- Federico, calm down.
Let go of me. I'll kill that animal!
- Federico!
- Federico! Don't be impulsive!
How dare you attack my son!
How dare me attack your son?
You shouldn't be saying that to me.
You should say that to this animal, your son!
Wait, how did you know each other?
We don't know each other.
But that face... I remember that face!
He killed your wife, Alyanna.
And he is the reason
why Florence ended with us.
- Federico...
- Calm down, Federico.
That is a very serious accusation.
Do you have any evidence
to accuse us of that crime?
I was there.
I was there in the area
where Alyanna was killed.
I'm sorry, Celestina.
Mommy has to go.
Just stay here first.
I love you so much.
I love you...
I love you.
I love you, Celestina.
Maybe Alyanna escaped from you that night.
She knew the situation was dangerous,
that's why she couldn't do anything,
but protect her daughter!
Wait, where is the hospital
you're talking about?
Over there. It's Mary Grace Hospital.
Wait, we're not going there.
This is going out of Levante.
- Get down.
- Uncle Samuel, why do you have that?
Don't ask too many questions. Get down!
Why are you doing this?
Florence, I just need you, so I can escape.
So I can get money from your grandpa
and your daddy...
because I wanted to start again,
and stay away from you.
You will pay for all your sins.
Why?
What do you know about my sins?